and so now Graham has 10 meditations we will
already do it will be 27 before the start of
your retreat is called the earth this is the
basis and the inner essence to keep the vows of
refuge the first
first calls jumping what we discussed with you this
refuge lunch invites is necessary in
order to follow further on any
path in Odessa
all subsequent lunch and bodhisattvas
monastic secret they begin with the
vows of refuge and these
lunch and refuges they are the
foundation with the earth from which all
other trees
once I planted an iris in
my garden I grew pink and
purple the soil in my garden
will be 90 percent rocky very
so rocky that it takes
about two hours to plant a rose
after a few after a while
I see that these beautiful flowers and I am
trying to understand how you such rocky
land could have such beautiful
flowers and somehow this
sprout that I planted
somehow sucked out the necessary substances and
put them into the petals of the flowers and not in the
style of the stem but specifically in  petals,
this seems incomprehensible, and here is Karen Po's shoulder strap, a
person says that in Buddhism,
everything is built in the same way. You take
these vows of refuge,
and then a bouquet of various beautiful flowers grows from them. And
refuge is the earth from
which everything grows. They will forgive all the
beautiful flowers,
and how
successful your practice will be will
depend on how
well you take the vow of refuge. This is the
soil from which everything will grow, no matter what
you do.
If you take refuge, if it is
strong, then all the results that you
plant will be great.
I want to tell you about my flowers from
bird droppings. People often ask
why dishonest people become
rich. Why dishonest people
succeed. And the answer to this is that by chance, the
seed that sprouted in their
garden. I wanted to plant some kind of tree in my garden,
and it was not my
gardening partner who did not allow me to do this, but
suddenly we want to plant. We see that it is
just a sprout. We look at this and see
that this is the tree itself, but I do not  I was
planting it, I asked how it happened,
how it sprouted,
and my partner said that this tree was made of
bird droppings, some
bird was flying until it fell on the ground, and
from this a tree grew,
and I came to
this tree, it grew 3 meters in height,
but rats came and gnawed at the
roots, and one day I approached this tree, and
I dreamed that it leaned towards this tree,
this happened because the
roots were eaten by these rats, and this is an
example of what happens when you have
weak roots, if you do not understand
refuge, if you do not understand what it is, then
any of your practices will not be strong,
and you can one day attach such a
prize to an enchanting experience, then when you have already
grown to this tree and
suddenly you see something